University Information Technology Records UA161
Tufts Archival Research Center
University Information Technology Records
1984 -- 2019
Tufts Archival Research Center
Tufts Computing and Communications Services
University Information Technology
Kahle, David J.
UA161
10.08 Linear Feet 14 boxes
24 Digital Object(s) 17 of the 24 digital objects comprise 3,838 files.
23.4 Gigabytes
University Information Technology (UIT) is a university-wide service dedicated to the strategic planning, implementation and support of technical products and services for the Tufts community. This collection contains records of UIT and the Office of the Chief Information Officer, including reports, brochures, posters, presentations, communications, meeting minutes, photos and videos.
Conditions Governing Access
University records are closed for 20 years from the date of their creation. Records older than 20 years that do not pertain to student education, staff and faculty employment and Board of Trusteees records are open for research. This collection may require review before it is available for use. Please contact DCA or further details.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred by the University Information Technology Office, 2008 -- 2021.
Appraisal
Go-Pro videos of a Tufts Technology Services bowling outing that were part of accession UA-2020-052 were not retained due to their large file size and lack of research value. Records and Accessioning Archivist, Jane Kelly, contacted the Office of the Chief Information Officer to inform them of this decision and ensure they had access to the original files if necessary.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in received order in three series: Additional accessions, the Office of the Chief Information Officer records, and Library Technology Services records.
Biographical / Historical
University Information Technology (UIT) is a university-wide service dedicated to the strategic planning, implementation and support of technical products and services that anticipate and meet the academic and business needs of the Tufts community. Under the direction of the Vice President and Chief Information Officer, UIT delivers information technologies to the university that faciliate teaching, learning, research, administration and outreach.
Scope and Contents
University Information Technology (UIT) is a university-wide service dedicated to the strategic planning, implementation and support of technical products and services that anticipate and meet the academic and business needs of the Tufts community. This collection contains the records of UIT and the Office of the Chief Information Officer including reports, brochures, posters, presentations, communications, meeting minutes, photos, and videos.
Information Systems; University history
- Additional accessions, 1993 -- 2012; UA161.001; 7 Digital Object(s); 7.27 Megabytes
  - Strategic plans, budget proposals and reports; TCCS five year plan, Turn Futility into Utility pamphlet, and Strategic Plan, 1993 -- 2008; UA161-001 (Box 1)
    Conditions Governing Access
    20 years from date of creation.
    - Strategic Plan, 2008; UA161-001.00001
  - ITC/TCCS binders and general IT policies, 1997 -- 2002; UA161-002 (Box 2)
  - ITC/TCCS binders and general IT policies, 1997 -- 1999; UA161.000037 (Box 6)
    Open for research.
    Immediate Source of Acquisition
    Transferred by Charlotte Keys, 2010, accession 2010.093.
  - Mobile Mindfulness posters and tote bag and pen/paper; Compute Safely brochures, 2012; UA161-005; 5 Digital Object(s); 3.9 Megabytes (Box 3)
    - Mobile Mindfulness posters, 2012; UA161-005.00001; 5 Digital Object(s); 3.9 Megabytes
  - Tufts Technology Services files, 1988 -- 2007; UA161-006 (Box 4)
    Scope and Contents
    Tufts Technology Services newsletters and brochures, TAB survival kit, Next Generation Directory, and Trusted Identity Management Committee records.
  - Tufts Identity Management Steering (TIMS) committee, 2003 -- 2005; UA161-007
    Identity Management Steering committee
  - Strategic plans, budget proposal, and reports, 1993 -- 2001; UA161.000036 (Box 5)
- Office of the Chief Information Officer records, 1998 -- 2019; UA161.000011; 23.4 Gigabytes; 17 Digital Object(s) 17 digital objects comprising 3,838 files.; 6.83 Linear Feet
  Transferred by the Office of the Chief Information Officer, 2020 -- 2021, accessions UA-2020-052 and UA-2022-012.
  This series contains records from the Office of the Chief Information Officer. These records include presentations, reports, communications, meeting minutes, photos, and videos. The material dates from 1998 to 2019, which includes David J. Kahle's tenure as Tufts' Vice President for Information Technology and Chief Information Officer from 2009 to 2018. These records document the Office of the Chief Information Officer and Tufts Technology Services (TTS) more generally, including records of committees and external partnerships, strategic and project planning, presentations and documentation about TTS for Tufts faculty and staff, photographs of TTS outings and staff events, New England Association of Schools and Colleges accreditation documents, disaster planning, financial records, and information on hiring and personnel.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged in received order in one sub-series: David J. Kahle records.
  - David J. Kahle records, 1998 -- 2019; UA161.000028; 23.4 Gigabytes; 17 Digital Object(s) 17 digital objects comprising 3,838 files.; 6.83 Linear Feet
    - Administrative files and video footage of David Kahle, 2015 -- 2019; UA161.000012; 2.6 Gigabytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 6 files.
      This folder originally contained one file about TTS. Files that were not within a folder were bundled with this single item and video footage of David Kahle.
    - Annual Report for Executive Vice President's Office, 2014 -- 2016; UA161.000013; 105.3 Kilobytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 3 files.
      Annual reports for the Executive Vice President's Office.
    - Design, 2015 -- 2017; UA161.000014; 14.1 Megabytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 5 files.
      Documents related to Tufts Technology Services' design thinking and service design practices.
    - Memories of David J. Kahle, 2014 -- 2018; UA161.000015; 1.9 Gigabytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 16 files.
      Photos, videos, and other material related to former Tufts Chief Information Officer David J. Kahle's memorial.
    - New England Association of Schools and Colleges accreditation, 2013 -- 2019; UA161.000016; 5.4 Megabytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 11 files.
      Tufts Technology Services reports and contributions to the NEASC Accreditation process, including documents related to the School of the Museum of Fine Arts and Tufts' NEASC 5 Year Interim Report.
    - Office of the Chief Information Officer key presentations, 2011 -- 2018; UA161.000017; 3.8 Gigabytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 614 files.
      Meeting presentations and supporting documents for faculty, staff, trustees, and Tufts' executive leadership. Presentations cover information security audits, administration and finance, IT support, and town hall updates.
    - Office of the Chief Information Officer meetings, 2011 -- 2018; UA161.000018; 3.6 Gigabytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 1,321 files.
      Presentations and related documents for meetings with various groups. These groups include: Administration & Planning Subcommittee, external partners and groups, CIO Council, Digital Humanities - Support Structures for Programs at Tufts, Enterprise Operations, Executive Vice President Staff Council, Faculty IT Liaison Program, IT Advisory Committee, IT Leaders Forum, Provost's Office, Support Services Steering Team, Trustees, Tufts Library Council, and University Risk and Compliance Committee.
    - Operations, 2011 -- 2018; UA161.000019; 26.6 Megabytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 28 files.
      Records of IT operations, including material related to the Federal Communications Commission, Tufts Service Desk Requests for Proposals, the School of the Museum of Fine Arts, and the Tufts network. Also includes records created by Compliance Process Partners, LLC, related to IT Service Management at Tufts.
    - Orientation materials for senior leadership, 2015; UA161.000020; 15.4 Megabytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 6 files.
      Presentations and reports about Tufts Technology Services for members of the senior leadership at Tufts.
    - ProvostOffice-Connect, 2011 -- 2017; UA161.000021; 524.3 Megabytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 59 files.
      Documents related to video conferencing and collaboration tools, including WebEx and Box.
    - Tufts Effectiveness in Administrative Management (TEAM), 2012 -- 2016; UA161.000022; 41 Megabytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 772 files.
      Meeting documents related to communications, program plans, IT resources, customer satisfaction metrics, strategic plans, IT organizational structure, organizational design and personnel, and executive committee meetings.
    - Tufts Technology Services communications, 2010 -- 2018; UA161.000023; 2.2 Gigabytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 267 files.
      Staff newsletters, memos, and presentations.
    - Tufts Technology Services forums, 2015 -- 2018; UA161.000024; 4.4 Gigabytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 112 files.
      Presentations and videos from monthly Tufts Technology Services Forums.
    - Tufts Technology Services photos, 2015 -- 2018; UA161.000025; 4.1 Gigabytes; 2 Digital Object(s) 2 digital objects comprising 610 files.
      Photographs from Tufts Technology Services social events, including holiday parties and summer outings.
    - Tufts Technology Services service disruption reports, 2014 -- 2016; UA161.000026; 135.9 Kilobytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 4 files.
      Reports about disruptions to TTS services.
    - Tufts Distinction Awards - Tufts Technology Services submissions, 2014 -- 2017; UA161.000027; 518.1 Kilobytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising 4 files.
      Tufts Technology Services submissions to the Tufts Distinction Awards, which recognize the exceptional accomplishments of faculty and staff.
    - Project and planning records, 2005 -- 2013; UA161.000039 (Box 7)
      Records relating to Tufts Technology Services projects and strategic planning. Projects include Tufts Effectiveness in Administrative Management (TEAM) records, IT business continuity planning, research administration systems, Visual Understanding Environment 2.0 (VUE 2.0) records, Student Information System (SIS) records, TTS reorganization and strategic planning documents, and online course development records.
    - Project and planning records, 2004 -- 2008; UA161.000040 (Box 8)
      Meeting minutes, notes, and reports related to Tufts Technology Services projects and ongoing business, including physical space planning, academic technology, surveys, university information technology support, library technology, and strategic planning.
    - Academic technology, disaster planning, and financial records, 2002 -- 2009; UA161.000041 (Box 9)
      Academic technology records, business continuity and disaster planning, and budget and audit records.
    - Digital media and VHS tapes, circa 1999 -- 2010; UA161.000042 (Box 10)
      CD-Rs, DVDs, 3.5" floppy disks, mini DV, and 120 MB Super Disks containing files related to Visual Understanding Environment (VUE), Best Practices: Introducing the Videopaper, disaster recovery planning, ArcGIS data, and other Tufts Technology Services projects.
    - Administrative and project planning records, 1998 -- 2010; UA161.000043 (Box 11)
      Budget and strategic planning records, services statistics and metrics, student information system (SIS) records, and learning management system records.
    - Administrative and project planning records, 1998 -- 2009; UA161.000044 (Box 12)
      Budget and strategic planning records; student information system (SIS) and PeopleSoft records; Academic, Administrative, and Information Technology Councils meeting notes and reports; Tufts Computing and Communications Services (TCCS) reports and planning documents; academic technology presentations and reports; and TTS project documentation.
    - Administrative and project planning records, 1998 -- 2018; UA161.000045 (Box 13)
      Academic technology reports, Tufts Effectiveness in Administrative Management (TEAM) records; research computing and data strategy reports, statistics, and correspondence; accreditation documents; University IT brochures, booklets, and reports; budget proposals; and TTS project documentation.
    - Project planning records, 1999 -- 2005; UA161.000046 (Box 14)
      GIS systems, Tufts University Research Network (TuRN) Project, network infrastructure, and Visual Understanding Environment (VUE) records.
- Library Technology Services records, 1984 -- 2017; UA161.000029; 3 Linear Feet; 9.61 Gigabytes
  Transferred by Library Technology Services, 2021 -- 2022, accessions UA-2022-010, UA-2022-021, and UA-2022-041.
  This series is arranged in received order.
  This series contains records created by Library Technology Services (LTS). The bulk of the material consists of records from library teams, working groups, and committees that involved LTS staff. These groups relate to library automation, networking, metadata, and include the University Library Council, Digital Collections & Archives Advisory Committee, Library Systems Council, Web Advisory Group, and Services Steering Team. Records in this series also relate to capital campaigns, budgets, reorganization planning, and the Fedora repository implementation. There is also one box of audio-visual material, slides, and digital media.
  - University Library Council and Integrated Library Managment System Task Force records, 2007 -- 2016; UA161.000030 (Box 1)
  - Library teams and working groups records, 1985 -- 2014; UA161.000031 (Box 2)
  - Library teams and working groups records, 1984 -- 2012; UA161.000032 (Box 3)
  - "Supporting a future of data-intensive studies through strengthening digital capabilities today" draft, 2017 November 03; UA161.000033 (Shared 150, Folder 1)
  - Library Technology Services digital media, circa 1996 -- 2009; UA161.000034 (Box 4)
    Three VHS tapes, one labeled "Reduced 'Collaboration': A pair and four trios. 10 July 96"; thirteen mini DVs; one Premium 125P data cartridge; one box of slides with images of computer terminal and presentation about computers; seven Zip disks; and 21 CD-Rs and DVD-Rs. Contents of disks is unclear but may include course material or lecture recordings.
  - Tufts Digital Repository poster, circa 2005; UA161.000035 (Box Large Map Case 3 Drawer 9)